<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Risk Sharing | Tomoaki Yamada</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/ja/tag/risk-sharing/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/ja/tag/risk-sharing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Risk Sharing</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>ja-jp</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/media/icon_hu36ba55165b33871ce773f917143a2da3_8669_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Risk Sharing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ja/tag/risk-sharing/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Note on Risk Sharing against Idiosyncratic Shocks and Geographic Mobility in Japan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ja/project/yamada_2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ja/project/yamada_2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this study, using Japanese household panel data, we analyze how well idiosyncratic income risks are shared by regions. We find that geographic mobility influences individual consumption growth rates, suggesting that complete asset markets fail to exist. We reject the full insurance hypothesis for both urban and rural areas and find that the extent of risk sharing differs significantly by region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MPRA Paper, No. 54886, 2014.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can Cross-Border Financial Markets Create Good Collateral in a Crisis?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ja/project/saito_suzuki_yamada_2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ja/project/saito_suzuki_yamada_2010/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we explore whether markets can create endogenously good collateral in a crisis by analyzing a simple exchange economy where a country-specific catastrophic shock is shared between two countries. To see this possibility, we examine whether the equilibrium achieved by the time-0 complete markets with solvency constraints can be recovered in the dynamically complete markets with collateral constraints. This paper demonstrates that it is possible to recover the time-0 equilibrium outcome in a sequential manner when pricing errors occur randomly in evaluating Lucas trees at a catastrophic event. Such stochastic components may be interpreted as a policy initiative to create good collateral and yield constrained efficient outcomes at crisis periods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IMES Discussion Paper Series, 2010-E-19, 2010.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Intergenerational Sharing of Cohort-Specific Shocks on Permanent Income</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ja/publication/miyazaki_saito_yamada_md_2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ja/publication/miyazaki_saito_yamada_md_2010/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- 

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click the &lt;em&gt;Cite&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo the feature to enable visitors to import publication metadata into their reference management software.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
 --&gt;
&lt;!-- 

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Create your slides in Markdown - click the &lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt; button to check out the example.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
 --&gt;
&lt;!-- Supplementary notes can be added here, including [code, math, and images](https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/). --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
