<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Inequality | Tomoaki Yamada</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/ja/tag/inequality/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/ja/tag/inequality/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Inequality</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>ja-jp</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/media/icon_hu36ba55165b33871ce773f917143a2da3_8669_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Inequality</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ja/tag/inequality/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Time Trend and Life-cycle Profiles of Consumption</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ja/publication/kitao_yamada_reho_2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ja/publication/kitao_yamada_reho_2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This paper analyzes the time trend of household consumption in Japan between 1981 and 2020, using microdata from the Family Income and Expenditure Survey (FIES). We examine how the trends in the levels, shares, and growth of consumption vary across categories of consumption, items and age groups, and assess changes in consumption inequality over time. Our analysis shows that consumption inequality mildly increased, driven primarily by the trend of service consumption. Additionally, we estimate the life-cycle profiles of consumption and find that the age component of total consumption follows a standard hump-shaped pattern, but varies significantly across goods and service categories and item groups. Finally, using the estimated age profiles of different consumption items, we project how aggregate consumption and its composition may evolve as Japan’s population ages in the coming decades.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dimensions of Inequality in Japan: Distributions of Earnings, Income and Wealth between 1984 and 2014</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ja/project/kitao_yamada_rieti_2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ja/project/kitao_yamada_rieti_2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Inequality has become a central policy issue around the world. We study trends of inequality in earnings, income and wealth across households in Japan, using the National Survey of Family Income and Expenditure (NSFIE) from 1984 to 2014. We focus on the transition of inequality unconditionally and conditionally across various dimensions of household heterogeneity such as age, cohort, employment and marital status of household heads, sources of income, family size, etc. Inequality in earnings, income and wealth all increased during the last three decades. Changes in earnings and income inequality were mostly driven by demographic shift in the population towards the elderly, who tend to have higher inequality. Wealth inequality rose not only in the aggregate but also among the young, and this is due to a major increase in the fraction of households who own zero or very low wealth across all age groups. Critical factors in understanding inequality trends in Japan that we identified are aging demographics, changes in typical household structure, and macroeconomic trends of the past decades including the financial bubble period and a decades-long slow-down thereafter.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Monetary Policy Shocks on Inequality in Japan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ja/project/inui_sudo_yamada/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ja/project/inui_sudo_yamada/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The impacts of monetary easing on inequality have been attracting increasing attention recently. In this paper, we use the micro-level data on Japanese households to study the distributional effects of monetary policy. We construct quarterly series of income and consumption inequality measures from 1981 to 2008, and estimate their response to a monetary policy shock. We find that monetary policy shocks do not have a statistically significant impact on inequality across Japanese households in a stable manner. When considering inequality across households whose head is employed, we find evidence that, before the 2000s, an expansionary monetary policy shock increased income inequality through a rise in earnings inequality. Such procyclical responses are, however, scarcely observed when the current data are included in the sample period, or when earnings inequality across all households is considered. We also find that transmission of income inequality to consumption inequality is minor, including during the period when procyclicality of income inequality was pronounced. Using a two-sector dynamic general equilibrium model with attached labor inputs, we show that labor market flexibility is central to the dynamics of income inequality after monetary policy shocks. We also use the micro-level data on households&amp;rsquo; balance sheets and show that distributions of households&amp;rsquo; financial assets and liabilities do not play a significant role in the distributional effects of monetary policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BIS Working Papers, No. 642, 2017.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bank of Japan Working Paper Series, No. 17-E-3, 2017.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Intergenerational Sharing of Cohort-Specific Shocks on Permanent Income</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ja/publication/miyazaki_saito_yamada_md_2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ja/publication/miyazaki_saito_yamada_md_2010/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- 

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click the &lt;em&gt;Cite&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo the feature to enable visitors to import publication metadata into their reference management software.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
 --&gt;
&lt;!-- 

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Create your slides in Markdown - click the &lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt; button to check out the example.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
 --&gt;
&lt;!-- Supplementary notes can be added here, including [code, math, and images](https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/). --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
