<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Population | Tomoaki Yamada</title>
    <link>https://tomoakiyamada.github.io/tag/population/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://tomoakiyamada.github.io/tag/population/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Population</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://tomoakiyamada.github.io/media/icon_hu36ba55165b33871ce773f917143a2da3_8669_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Population</title>
      <link>https://tomoakiyamada.github.io/tag/population/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demographic Aging, Fiscal Reforms and Macroeconomy in Japan</title>
      <link>https://tomoakiyamada.github.io/project/yamada_2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tomoakiyamada.github.io/project/yamada_2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Presented at the ESRI International Conference 2023.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Under revision.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Population Aging and Redistribution in Japan: Comparisons with OLG, SNA and NTA</title>
      <link>https://tomoakiyamada.github.io/project/ichimura_yamada/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tomoakiyamada.github.io/project/ichimura_yamada/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Presented at the Computing in Economics and Finance in 2021 at Keio University&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dimensions of Inequality in Japan: Distributions of Earnings, Income and Wealth between 1984 and 2014</title>
      <link>https://tomoakiyamada.github.io/project/kitao_yamada_rieti_2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tomoakiyamada.github.io/project/kitao_yamada_rieti_2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Inequality has become a central policy issue around the world. We study trends of inequality in earnings, income and wealth across households in Japan, using the National Survey of Family Income and Expenditure (NSFIE) from 1984 to 2014. We focus on the transition of inequality unconditionally and conditionally across various dimensions of household heterogeneity such as age, cohort, employment and marital status of household heads, sources of income, family size, etc. Inequality in earnings, income and wealth all increased during the last three decades. Changes in earnings and income inequality were mostly driven by demographic shift in the population towards the elderly, who tend to have higher inequality. Wealth inequality rose not only in the aggregate but also among the young, and this is due to a major increase in the fraction of households who own zero or very low wealth across all age groups. Critical factors in understanding inequality trends in Japan that we identified are aging demographics, changes in typical household structure, and macroeconomic trends of the past decades including the financial bubble period and a decades-long slow-down thereafter.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Demographic Change on the Expenditure Composition in Japanese Economy</title>
      <link>https://tomoakiyamada.github.io/project/sudo_suzuki_yamada_2014b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tomoakiyamada.github.io/project/sudo_suzuki_yamada_2014b/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work in progress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
